Fauquier County School Board records, 1986-1996
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Fauquier County School Board records
1986-1996
C0211
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This collection contains the records of the Fauquier County School Board compiled from the papers of Lawrence D. Czarda, a member of the school board. The majority of the collection consists of correspondence, memorandums, reports, fiscal plans, drafts, transparencies, and data charts and graphs.
Fauquier County School Board
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the records of the Fauquier County School Board compiled from the papers of Lawrence D. Czarda, a member of the school board. The majority of the collection consists of correspondence, memorandums, reports, fiscal plans, drafts, transparencies, and data charts and graphs. To a lesser extent, the collection also consists of agendas, proposals, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, newsletters, bulletins, brochures, resolutions, maps, business cards, calendars, and floppy disks. Subjects of interest include the history of Fauquier schools, membership and population projections, expenditures and revenues, the middle school movement and the controversy of grade configurations in the schools, facility needs, Lord Fairfax Community College-- Fauquier campus, and attracting businesses to the county. The collection is dated from 1986 to 1996 and consists of three boxes. It is arranged alphabetically by subject title.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Lawrence D. Czarda.
Related Material
Special Collections & Archives also holds the that contain information on the Fairfax County School Board.
Historical Note
The Fauquier County School Board's responsibilities dictated by the statutes of Virginia and the regulations of the Virginia Board of Education are to operate the public schools of Fauquier County by providing them with policy for the day-to-day supervision of schools, establishing goals and objectives for each aspect of the school system's operation based upon the identified needs of the community, and to provide a framework of general rules and guidelines for school system administration affecting major educational and financial issues of the Fauquier County School Division. The five School Board members are elected for four-year terms; one member represents each of the county's five magisterial (election) districts.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Fauquier County (Va.)
Subjects:
Education, Higher--Virginia.; Public schools--Virginia.; School boards.
Contents List
- Fauquier County School Board Records, 1986-1996
  - Capital Improvement Program, FY 1991-1996 -- Arlington County, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Capital Improvement Program, FY 1991-1996 -- Prince William County, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Capital Improvement Program, FY 92/93-96/97 -- Fauquier County (Folder 1), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Capital Improvement Program, FY 92/93-96/97 -- Fauquier County (Folder 2), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Capital Improvement Program, FY 92/93-96/97 -- Fauquier County (Folder 3) -- Floppy Disks, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chamber of Commerce -- Who's Who in Business, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Demographic Projects, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Demographic Projects, Duplicates, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Education Center, 1990-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - FCSB/IET Partnership, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Giant Food and Sainsburg, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Management Information System, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Maps and Capital Improvements, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meetings, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Outside Studies, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Public Schools: A Comprehensive Study of School System Facilities, February 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - School Board -- Book Appeal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - School Board Task Force, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - State Agency Session, July 26-27, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - State Post Secondary Review Entity (SPRE) Project, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Warrenton/ Fauquier Chamber of Commerce Committees, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Warrenton Town Counsel Committees, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Working Draft, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Working Draft, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Working Group #1, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Working Group #2, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Working Group #4, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Working Group #5, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Working Group #6, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Working Group #7, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Working Group #8, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)